Exercise 1-20. Variable Stress. Notice how the meaning of the following sentence
changes each time we change the stress pattern. You should be starting to feel in
control of your sentences now. 1. What would you like? This is the most common
version of the sentence and it's just a simple request for information. 2. What
would you like? This is to single out an individual from a group. 3. What would you
like? You have been discussing the kinds of things that he might like and you want
to determine his specific desires. Now that you mention it, what would you like?
Or he has rejected several things and a little exasperated you ask, if you don't
want any of these, what would you like? 4. What would you like? You didn't hear and
you'd like the speaker to repeat herself. Or you can't believe what you just heard.
strawberry jam on my asparagus? What would you like? Repeat the four sentences.